<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on A Software Developer's CV</title><link>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on A Software Developer's CV</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 19:14:48 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Personal Data</title><link>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/personal-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 19:14:48 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/personal-data/</guid><description>Personal information about me: Name: Navroop Singh
Email: navroops806@gmail.com
Contact Number: 0432334576
Location: Melbourne, VIC
Click one of these to get to know my candidature better:
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/navroop-singh-b985aa16a/ Github: https://github.com/navroopsinghsandhu Upwork: https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~01d91723ff85b04627</description></item><item><title>Work Experience</title><link>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/my-experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 19:10:34 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/my-experience/</guid><description>Active Interactive - Jamables Social Music App Role: Application Developer
Location: - Remote Work
Duration: June 2021 – December 2021
Responsibilities:
Requirement gathering /coordination with client Jambot page to teleport to a different location using maps,create/remove a jambot and additional features Improved synchronisation by implementing native codes through plugins for both android and ios platforms Developed user interfaces to provide music library, easy way to join a friend’s jam and show user’s data within a jam Publishing the app on android and ios app stores Updated graphics and resolved existing UI bugs in the system as a part of code maintenance Followed the process of versioning, regression testing and releasing/uploading new versions to play store and app store Learnings and upskilling: Working on this project has helped me grow in various aspects of my life as a developer.</description></item><item><title>Skills</title><link>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/my-skills/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 19:10:24 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/my-skills/</guid><description>Programming is never limilted to one language and my goal as a software developer has always been to also concentrate on a technology independent learning along with learning the language itself, building the aptitude for clear understanding and learning in multiple technologies while building a strong base in one technology that can serve the organisation that I work for. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of technologies that I have worked on during my career as a software developer:</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/my-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 18:31:58 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/my-projects/</guid><description>I have been part of multiple projects and almost all of them involved team work and timely delivery to client. Apart from the technical skills, I learned to design the timeline for the development phase with emphasis on better execution in programming, testing, debugging and resolving issues. I also learned the importance of communication and coordination within a team which increased the productivity in my work and the quality of product.</description></item><item><title>Education</title><link>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/my-education/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 18:31:25 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://navroopsinghsandhu.github.io/myportfolio/posts/my-education/</guid><description>RMIT University Program: MASTER OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY
Location: Melbourne, VIC, Australia
Duration: 28th Feb 2022 – Present
Chandigarh Engineering College(PTU) Program: BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY
Location: Mohali, Punjab, IN
Duration: Aug 2015 – Jun 2019
GPA: 7.33</description></item></channel></rss>